They'll call to order the regular meeting of the United States Council for March 7, 2022, but
input or any unscheduled personal experiences, we have none.
Three can sit and Jim the staff recommends we approve on this four and five.
Make a motion to approve?
Second.
We say aye.
Aye.
Six.
Resolution C.C. 22, that's year four.
MSU-A, 2022, that's year one on the Joint Resolution Delagant Summit claims payment,
so according to the City Manager and Trust Manager, it would be the same moment we both
want to.
And then it makes you ready.
So I'll make a motion to approve?
Aye.
Please stand.
Seven.
Wendy Gillesmy from Pet Division Property LLC has presented a approved claim of $20
record easement at the federal county clerk's office.
Post your approved?
Second.
Please stand.
Aye.
abstain.
Lettersupport for CTAs Grant for the MIMA Tribe.
So you have a copy of the letter at your place.
The MIMA Tribe is applying through federal program.
It came up with some money for a detention facility.
Other tribes are joining in.
And the hope is that two or more of the tribes can get separate grants, and then as they did
with the Health Center, out east of town, combined their money together, and make a better facility
they want either one of them individually.
And they are asking that we endorse this program through this letter, they are asking
the same of the county, and they feel that their chances of getting the grants will be significantly
approved.
There is a demonstration that everybody will multiply just as well as the city and the county are
all in support of this particular program.
would they run it then?
Well, that's yet to be determined.
It's quite possible that it would be a trust
that would be created.
The almost impossible to do this,
I believe, without the sheriff being involved.
But exactly how we're going to proceed.
That's yet to be determined.
But the idea is to get this grant application in
the nation, because the deadline is later this week.
And so we need to now, if we were to support this,
in a way that it counts as far as everybody is.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Davis.
Aye.
We stand.
Upspend.
Aye.
Any other new business that has risen?
Supposing this agenda.
Ten.
Mayor.
Council.
Community announcements.
Good.
Yeah.
I didn't know I'd get to go first.
Just because I'm sitting on this side.
Yeah.
All right.
So a couple of things.
I've been about halfway through the departments meeting with
the departments as part of my onboarding thing.
And I got to tell you, it's been awesome.
Just the level of input that I've gotten from everybody.
The willingness to want to work with us and us work with them.
It's just been refreshing that all these people and have such a passion for the city and have
a desire to be better and want to do the right thing.
I feel proud to be a representative of this community and the people that we have running our
municipality, right?
So I still have a few left to go, but I'm sure that it will be as equally as forthcoming with information
and willingness to want to work together.
So I just, I appreciate it.
It's been great.
And Jill is scared of you.
She was the first one I met with.
She was dealing with Jill did a great job and just gave me more information than I needed,
but there was information I wouldn't have known to ask for.
So I appreciated that she was very all of them.
I've been very thorough and just asked what I needed to know and what I, you know,
it's been very good so far.
I'm really glad that I've been able to do it and it's been a great bunch of people
that I met with.
I met with Travis and Chris today and community development.
And they were talking about some of the positive things they have coming up in their group.
And I mean that's a challenging department.
I would not want my worst enemy to have to work.
there, but you know, there's a no, that's a no-win situation in that case, you know, when
we're talking about a statement, I think at some point we will get some consistency there with
some of the things they're doing and I think that the city will start realizing that this is
for the benefit of them rather than it's just coming and pestering people, you know, because I think
that's, that's what it comes across through them now, like on the American, I can do what I want,
you can't tell me what my yard should look like, but, you know, the day we're proud of where we live
and we want it to look good, so other people would want to come and live here, right?
So, I admire those guys because they, they have a thankless job and they do a good job at it and
they've got some new things coming with employees that are starting up and being positive, so
and then I had a good time with the capital, would you guys, for those of us that got to go?
Yeah. I'm sure you guys will have some things to say, it was just refreshing to be down there
and see the process that it takes to make a bill into a law, it's not as simple as the cartoon
talking about, I'm just a bill, I mean, then you obviously lived it for a good portion of your life,
but what the cartoon? So we all talk about how the political system is slow and it's tough to
get anything done but once you sit on that floor and see the process, you have an understanding for it
of what it's like and why it is like it is because you get so much input on the laws that are
going to rule our land, right? And it should be, there should be a lot of people involved and there
should be a lot of opinions and there should be a lot of thought behind them because, you know,
if you just blow something through because, you know, you thought it was a good idea, it could have an effect on
people that you don't think about it in your own mind and then see you get the other people's input and you
do some debates and in the debates at the beginning, you know, you think well I'm totally this way and then you start
debating and then you hear other perspectives and then you think maybe I'm not totally this way, so it was
really cool, I enjoyed it, learned a lot and it was definitely valuable, so it's all the got.
I just want to welcome Melinda the board, maybe we can keep him off Facebook.
Right now.
It was a nice trip, it was eye opening, the net working was really cool, I'm sure one of you are going to tackle the
other item that was really fun to see and hard to believe that we haven't been.
engaged in that venue before now, but we weren't, we're not fix that and move forward.
So, we'll see.
Yeah, it was a good trip.
It was an eye opener for sure of how that process works.
We got to meet with Steve Bayshore for about three hours.
Just us in the room and got to pull it up, pull it in his ear,
and voice our opinion done some stuff.
And he told us what was coming.
When we were on a floor, we debated four bills, five bills.
Yeah.
That day.
It was four hours.
It took us four hours to debate those five bills.
And Steve told us that this week they were doing 50 bills a day.
And I'm like, wow, I don't know how to heck you do that.
Because it was really nice to meet people from other communities.
Some bigger, some smaller.
But we face a lot of the same issues, no matter what size you are.
But it also gave us opportunities to meet people that we can contact with questions
and help one another with different projects or how they get them done.
They were surprised to see us when we walked in.
Everybody got coming over on my hand.
You got for my own.
And again, we're not ready for my own four.
So, I don't know if we've ever been there or not.
But the act like we were from another world or something.
But we got to pick up a bench from the city of Antarctica.
Both probably going to talk about that a little bit.
So that was a neat little deal.
I'll let him.
I'm sure he's probably going to be the more spectacular on that.
And so I'll let him do that.
The other thing I got is the middle school girls.
And the high school girls.
Both one powerlifting state championships today is a team.
So three years in a row, I believe.
So pretty big deal.
And we had a couple of individual champions, which is another big deal.
So Kudos to those girls and their efforts.
They put in.
It's got to be empowering for some of those girls.
Because I know what's got, say, Kyways, 118 pounds.
And she deadlift in 285.
So pretty impressive.
Personal record.
Yeah, personal record for her.
So it's cool.
And she placed fifth overall.
And so she was at a ballet competition last night.
Yeah, she wanted ballet competition on Sunday in a part of the championship on.
Or fifth place.
So crazy.
But.
Order for you.
That's all got.
So we'll move to 11 man city managers, communications.
So as the mayor had mentioned, it was really, really fantastic.
And when we went down to Oklahoma City,
the city of Anodarco presented the city of Miami with really, really nice metal.
Park bench that was inscribed with our city motto and city of my am on it.
It's sitting right in there by my office, but it was for our utility crew that went down
last year, year four.
And assistant city of Enadarco in a time of need.
And I'll tell you that their city manager can, of course, could not have been more
complimentary about our team and how hard they worked and how impressed they were with our
folks going down there and helping them at the level that they did.
And so this was just something that they wanted to do to show their thanks to the city
of mine.
It was really excited to work with the utility guys and see where we want to put this
and go off their their awards.
So anyway, that was really great and I made a great contact with the city of Enadarco out of
it.
Kenneth Corn, who was the previous Senator Corn, and sounds like he's going to be taken
on the new role of the USDA very soon and excited to have him as a resource and someone who
thinks very highly of mine, so great job to do utility guys and Tyler and all the hard work
those guys do and show him what mine is all about, so congrats.
The last thing I wanted to mention of course is Melinda Stotz.
It's extremely excited to welcome Melinda to our city team as our new communications manager.
We're thrilled to have her.
It's been a long time from what I hear since my mother has had a communications manager, but
she will be instrumental in helping us improve our transparency and develop a strong communication
strategy because as you all know, I think we all appear believe.
The key to a strong government is communication and transparency and so that's really going to
be one of our initiatives going forward is making sure that we're putting out accurate information,
consistent information, more information and really providing all the data and facts that everyone needs
to know in what you all use to make decisions every day, what I use to make decisions every
day, it's important that we share that information and you know always try to avoid doing
anything in a vacuum because that's not good government.
So I'm excited to have Melinda and her expertise who has had many years in media as a writer
for newspapers, most recently worked with Kasa and her family have been the member of this community
for many years so we're lucky to have her and I'm terribly excited for what I think she
is going to do for us for us all in help, all the divisions of the city so.
No pressure.
That was then all I had.
All right, I'm gonna raise this at 12 adjournment. So move. Second.